ILGWU David Dubinsky Correspondence 5780/002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU David Dubinsky Correspondence
1850-1981
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Dubinsky, David
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/002
219.11 cubic feet
218.5 linear ft.
Correspondence.
The David Dubinsky correspondence consists of five series arranged as indicated in the Scope and Content section. The original order of the collection, except for misfilings, has been maintained as it was found. The records were originally filed in the President's office at ILGWU headquarters building, 1710 Broadway, New York City. Upon Mr. Dubinsky's retirement as President in 1966, they were transferred into a storage area of that building until February of 1974, when they were removed to the newly established Archives. With the exception of David Dubinsky Personal Correspondence Series, those qualified to gain access to the Archives may freely consult the entire D.D. Collection. No documents have been removed except letters of potential autograph value and disintegrating newspaper clippings. In all cases, removed materials have been replaced by facsimile copies.
5490841
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 31, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
1892 Born February 22nd in Brest-Litovsk, then in Russia, son of Bezalel and Shaie Wishingrad Dobnievski. Moved to Lodz, where the family operated a bakery.
1903 Began to work in father's bakery after attending three terms in Hebrew Zionist school.
1907 Qualified as master baker and joined bakers' union, organized by the General Jewish Workers Union, the Bund. Served as secretary of the bakers' union. Arrested, together with 60 other members of the union, in the course of a strike; released after payment of 25 rubles by father. Left Lodz to live with an uncle in Brest-Litovsk; after three months returned to Lodz and rejoined the bakers' union.
1908 Arrested while attending an illegal meeting of the bakers and, as a second offender, exiled to a small Siberian village. Escaped and made his way to Chelyabinsk and from there to Lodz, working as a baker under an assumed name.
1910 Sailed, with an older brother, Chaira, to New York City.
1911 Arrived in NYC on January 1st. Lived on Lower East Side and became apprenticed to learn the cutter's craft. Accepted as a member of Local 10, Cutters' Union of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, on July 13th.
1914 Married Emma Goldberg, an undergarment operator and member of the ILGWU. (The couple had one child, a daughter, Jean.)
1918 Elected to executive board of Local 10.
1919 Elected vice-president of Local 10.
1920 Elected chairman of Local 10.
1921 Elected president of Local 10. Elected general manager (a new offic manager and secretary) of Local 10 in December.
1922 Elected vice president of ILGWU and member of General Executive Board.
1929 Elected General Secretary-Treasurer of ILGWU. Served as Acting President of ILGWU.
1932 Elected by GEB in June as President, following death of President Benjamin Schlesinger.
1934 Elected vice president of American Federation of Labor in October.
1935 Joined with John L. Lewis of Mine Workers and Sidney Hillman of Amalgamated Clothing Workers to form a Committee for Industrial Organization. First U.S. labor representative to the International Labor Organization.
1936 Joined in founding the American Labor Party in New York State. Served as Democratic Party elector for the ticket of Franklin D. Roosevelt and John N. Garner.
1944 Joined in founding Liberal Party.
1945 Elected vice president of American Federation of Labor.
1966 Offered resignation as President to GEB at meeting of March 14th, to take effect April 12th. Resignation effective June 15th, anniversary of date on which he was first elected President.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/002 AV: ILGWU David Dubinsky Audio Recordings 5780/002 MB: ILGWU David Dubinsky Memorabilia 5780/002 P: ILGWU David Dubinsky Photographs 5780/099: ILGWU Retiree Service Department, David Dubinsky Papers 5780/104: ILGWU David Dubinsky Foundation Records 5780/136: ILGWU David Dubinsky Scrapbooks 5780/179 MB: ILGWU David Dubinsky Memorabilia 5780/179 P: ILGWU David Dubinsky Photographs
Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5490841
- A, 1947-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A, 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- A, 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  I.c.w. American Civil Liberties Union on labor matters.
- Advertisements, 1932-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Amalgamated Bank of N.Y., 1933-1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  I.c.w. Adolph Held re Union loans (collection of money and payment of debts owed by Union).
- AFL, 1940-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7a-7c)
  I.c.w. Wm. Green, George Meany and Union officers on jurisdictional disputes between Union and AFL federal locals.
- AFL. Charters, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  I.c.w. John S. Martin re AFL Federal Local 22809, Doll & Toy Workers Union's desire to transfer to Union.
- AFL, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  I.c.w. John Martin re organizing activities of Union in Southeast area & re P.H. Hanes Knitting Co., Winston-Salem, N.C.
- AFL. Conventions, 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1a-1b)
- AFL. Conventions, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- AFL. Conventions, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Incl. adopted resolutions, report of Exec. Council, congratulatory messages to D.D. re his speech on anti-racketeering. (Incl. text)
- AFL. Conventions, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 4a-4b)
- AFL. Conventions, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- AFL. Executive Council, 1945-1950 (Box 2, Folder 6a-6c)
  I.c.w. D.D. as V.P. of AFL; NLRB decisions, 1937-41. Washington Emergency Memorandum, 1949; Exec. Council report, 1945; Report and Resolutions referred to Exec. Council 1947; correspondence. w. Richard Walsh, re jurisdictional disputes in Hollywood, 1946.
- AFL. Green, Wm., 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Corres., AFL releases & memos, misc. items in connection w. death of Green, 1952.
- AFL. Green, Wm., 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. copies of letters to Green from John L. Lewis re steel strike, 1949.
- AFL. Green, Wm., 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 3a-3b)
  Corres. re steel strike, 1949.
- AFL. Green, Wm., 1940-1944 (Box 3, Folder 4a-4c)
  Incl. total benefits paid by Union to members 1941-44; correspondence. pertaining to anti- labor legislation 1943; war effort by unions 1941 & correspondence. re Union affiliation with the AFL, 1940.
- AFL. Green, Wm., 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Incl. jurisdictional dispute bet. Union & AFL re knitgoods workers in Cleveland, 1937.
- AFL. Green, Wm., 1936 (Box 3, Folder 6a-6b)
  Incl. communication bet. D.D. & Green re decision of the Exec. Council of AFL that the Union must withdraw from CIO, or face AFL suspension; decision of GEB re matter; correspondence. re AFL convention, Tampa, Fla., Nov. 1936; Union resolutions & communication bet. L. Hendin & D.D.; correspondence. re amount of benefits paid by Union to members, 1930-36.
- AFL. Green, Wm., 1935 (Box 4, Folder 1a-1b)
  Aug. 1935-Dec. 1935. Incl. correspondence. on activities of American Legion during Union strike in So. Norwalk, Conn.; w. Green re Union organizers in Canada; Union resolutions to AFL convention.
- AFL. Green, Wm., 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 2a-2e)
  1933-July 1935. Reports of AFL Exec. Council; Union resolutions to AFL Convention 1934; correspondence. re jurisdictional dispute bet. Union & United Textile Workers, 1934.
- AFL. Lewis, Meyer L. (Western Dir. of AFL), 1937-1941 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- AFL. Meany, George (Secretary-Treas.), 1947-1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- AFL. Meany, George, 1939-1946 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- AFL. Misc., 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- AFL. Misc., 1945-1949 (Box 5, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl., correspondence. re AFL women's delegation to England to study women's role in industry under war conditions; participation of Maida Springer of Local 132.
- AFL. Misc., 1938-1944 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- AFL. Morrison, Frank (Secretary), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- AFL. Morrison, Frank (Secretary), 1933-1936 (Box 5, Folder 4a-4d)
  Incl. correspondence. re jurisdictional dispute, bet. Union & ACWA in Lansford, Pa., 1935. Corres. re charter to Cloak & Suit Salesmen of NYC, 1934.
- AFL. Releases, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 5a-5c)
- AFL. Telegrams to D.D. from members protesting Union proposal made to AFL Convention recommending that charters be withdrawn from unions in which Communists are in leadership (Red Amendment)., 1935 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- AFL. Union Label Trades Dept., 1938-1950 (Box 6, Folder 1a-1c)
- American Federation of Teachers, 1935-1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Domestic, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 3a-3b)
  Corres. w. committees & organizations on assistance to refugees; ltr. from Albert Einstein.
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Domestic, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  I.c.w. organizations on boycott of German goods.
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Domestic, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Incl. responses from individual to D.D.'s invitation to attend World Labor Athletic Carnival, Aug. 1936.
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Domestic, 1939-1947 (Box 6, Folder 6a-6c)
  Corres. w. organizations & individuals, filed alphabetically, A-C. Incl. American Friends of German Freedom, Anti-Nazi League, American Guild for German Cultural Freedom, Coat & Suit Industry Relief Fund.
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Domestic. D-M (Box 7, Folder 1a-1c)
  Incl. Dominican Republic Settlement Assoc., Friends of German Freedom, German-Jewish Children's Aid, Inc., Int'l. Relief Assoc., League Against Fascism & Dictatorship; publications from organizations & committees & newspaper clippings on Charles Coughlin & D.D.
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Domestic. N-Z (Box 7, Folder 2a-2b)
  Nat'l. Conference of Christians & Jews, Inc., Non-Sectarian Anti-Nazi League, Sephardic Refugee Committee.
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Domestic. ILGWU Non-Sectarian Refugee Fund, 1939-1941 (Box 7, Folder 3a-3c)
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Domestic. ILGWU Non-Sectarian Refugee Fund (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Incl. lists of members, contributions, newspaper clippings.
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Domestic. ILGWU and Non-Sectarian Fund. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Foreign, 1936-1942 (Box 8, Folder 1a-1c)
  I.c.w. organizations & individuals in France, Italy & Germany. Letters from "illegal German trade union groups."
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Foreign, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 2a-2b)
  Reports on conditions in Europe; report by Sir Walter Citrine on visit to Russia.
- Anti-Nazi, Anti-Fascist. Foreign (Box 8, Folder 2c-2d)
  Printed material, incl. publications of Labor Chest for Relief and Liberation of Workers of Europe, 1934-36; misc. reports, releases & broadsides.
- Applications, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Applications for positions in Union, A-D.
- Applications, E-J. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Applications, K-R. (Box 9, Folder 1a-1b)
- Applications, S-Z. (Box 9, Folder 2a-2b)
- Applications for position as organizer, A-0. (Box 9, Folder 3a-3c)
- Applications for position as organizer, P-Z. (Box 9, Folder 4a)
- Applications, misc. (Box 9, Folder 4a-4c)
- Assessments, Dues. (Box 9, Folder 5a-5c)
- Incl. assessments for American Labor Party; Union conventions, 1932-1940 (Box 10, Folder 1a-1b)
  Death Benefit Fund; institutions and labor causes; initiation tax, 10 cents Old Age Assessment; per capita tax; T.W.O.C. (Textile Workers Organizing Committee).
- Associations, 1933-1934 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Embroidery Mfrs. Protective Assoc., Inc., of N.J.
- Associations, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Infants & Children's Coat Assoc., Inc. Incl. collective agreements; NRA Code for Industry; & correspondence. w. George Alger (Impartial Chairman), Cloak, Suit & Skirt Industries.
- Associations, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Low Price Dress Assoc. Inc.
- Associations, 1933-1936 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Metropolitan Knitted Textile Assoc. Inc. Collective Agreement.
- Associations., 1932-1933 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Nat'l. Knitted Outerwear Assoc., Oct. 1933; Wholesale Dress Mfrs.' Assoc., 1932
- B-BE, 1947-1950 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- B-BE, 1938-1946 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- BI, 1938-1950 (Box 10, Folder 9a-9b)
  Incl. two letters from Louis Brandeis.
- B, 1936-1937 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- B-BI, 1934-1938 (Box 10, Folder 11a-11b)
  Incl. testimony by Louis Brandeis before Commission on Industrial Relations, April 1914.
- Bank of the United States, 1927-1933 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Incl. lists of Union deposits; record of settlement of claims.
- Billikopf, Jacob (Director), Labor Standards Assoc., 1939-1947 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  (Impartial Chairman) Ladies' Garment Industry of Phila., 1943
- Billings, Warren, 1939-1940 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  I.c.w. Warren Billings & w. the "Billings Defense Movement for His Pardon;" newsletters.
- British War Relief. (See (Box 11, Folder 4)
  (See W. World War II.)
- Brookwood Labor College, 1930-1938 (Box 11, Folder 5a-5c)
  Incl. correspondence. on finances.
- C-CL, 1947-1951 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- C-CL, 1933-1946 (Box 11, Folder 7a-7b)
  I.c.w. Marx Lewis (Secretary), Continental Congress for Economic Reconstruction.
- CO, 1947-1951 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- CO, 1939-1946 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- C, 1933-1948 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Census Reports, 1930-1939 (Box 12, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. census of local unions.
- Census Reports, 1924-1929 (Box 12, Folder 3a-3b)
- Central High School of Needle Trades, 1935-1945 (Box 12, Folder 4a-4c)
  I.c.w. Mortimer C. Ritter (Principal) & Max Meyer (Chairman), Needlecraft Educational Commission.
- Central Organization Dept., 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  Incl. Louis Stulberg's report on Pacific Coast visit, 1946.
- City Center of Music and Drama, Inc., 1943-1952 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Incl. financial reports.
- Clubs and Groups, Union (C & G), Locals 9, 10, 20, 22, 1938-1942 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Incl. broadsides, news releases, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, arranged by local.
- C and G. Local 60, Dress Pressers Club, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- C and G. Prolet Social Club, Inc. Incl. minutes, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Constitution of Club.
- C and G. Local 117 & Local 155 Knitgoods Workers. Union Vanguard Journal & related correspondence., 1939 (Box 13, Folder 5a-5b)
  Corres. on reinstatement of Jacob Katz; minutes of conference to create Progressive Trade Center
- C and G. Out-of-Town. (Box 13, Folder 6a-6b)
  Incl. GEB Comm. hearing of appeal by expelled Montreal members and its decision.
- Cohen, Max, Local 60, Dress and Waist pressers Union. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Corres. re death of M. Cohen.
- Cohen, Thomas (Engineer) (Box 13, Folder 8a-8b)
  Report on Canadian cloak markets, 1939; also schedule of piece work prices for blouses, cotton dresses & other studies, 1937-38.
- CIO, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Address by D.D. to Local 22, Jan. 1942; part of speech deals with peace in the labor movement.
- CIO, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 2a-2c)
  Corres. on "Memorandum on the Basis for Peace Negotiations bet. the AFL & the CIO," by S.D. Bercrer; Union pamphlet, ILGWU in relation to CIO & AFL 1934-38.
- CIO. Conferences, Meetings and Conventions, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 3a-3b)
  Apr.-Dec. 1938. Incl. telegrams pro & con GEB decision not to participate in CIO Pittsburgh convention, Nov. 14; text of resolution 11-11-38; correspondence. incl. John L. Lewis.
- CIO. Conferences, Meetings and Conventions, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 4a-4b)
  Jan.-Apr. 1938. Incl. correspondence. on newspaper & magazine articles on AFL- CIO split.
- CIO. Conferences, Meetings and Conventions, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 5a-5c)
  July-Dec. 1937. Corres. CIO Atlantic City Convention, Oct. 11-16, 1937.
- CIO, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 6a-6b)
  June-Dec. 1937.
- CIO, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 1a-1b)
  Jan.-May 1937.
- CIO, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 2a-2e)
  Aug.-Dec. 1936. Corres. on AFL-CIO controversy; incl. telegram (copy) sent to CIO affiliates re decision of GEB not to participate in AFL convention, Nov. 11, 1936; John Brophy report on CIO activities for 1936; exchange of telegrams bet. Wm. Green & CIO (CIO Pittsburgh meeting, Nov. 1939); AFL decision suspending CIO unions, Aug. 6, 1936; D.D. resignation as AFL V.P., September 1, 1936.
- CIO, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 3a-3c)
  Jan.-July 1936. Corres. re controversy; incl. AFL letters requesting CIO unions to appear before Executive Council; correspondence. re decision of AFL to CIO unions to withdraw from CIO; letters from Wm. Green urging CIO dissolution; correspondence. w. CIO, publi­cations.
- CIO, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 4a-4b)
  Nov.-Dec. 1935. Incl. correspondence. relating to formation of CIO, and Wm. Green's letters dealing w. it; minutes of CIO meeting, Nov. 1935; summary of meetings bet. sub-comm. of AFL & CIO, 1. of resignation from John L. Lewis as AFL V.P., correspondence. incl. John L. Lewis, Wm. Green, Sidney Hillman & Charles Howard.
- CIO. Comments on D.D.'s speech, "The CIO, AFL and Peace" before joint meeting of exec. bd. of N.Y. locals. (Box 16, Folder 1a-1c)
  text of speech.
- CIO. Industrial Union Councils, 1937-1939 (Box 16, Folder 2a-2c)
  April 1937-Aug. 1939. I.c.w. Union officers re affiliation w. CIO Industrial Union Councils, 1938-39; prior to 1938 correspondence. w. regional directors of CIO.
- CIO. Misc., 1937-1946 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  Incl. D.D. notes on CIO-AFL conference Oct.-Nov. (?)
- CIO. New York, 1937-1940 (Box 16, Folder 4a-4b)
  I.c.w. Allen Haywood (Regional Director); newspaper clippings on Communist elements in CIO.
- CIO. Printed material, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  Incl. Organizers Bulletin,
- CIO. Printed material, 1936-1942 (Box 16, Folder 6a-6d)
  Incl. AFL publication ,AFL vs CIO, The Record, Nov. 1939; CIO & Labor Unity, issued by the CIO, D.D. statement on unions suspended by AFL, 1936.
- Complaints, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 1a-1b)
- Complaints, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 2a-2c)
- Complaints, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 3a-3b)
- Complaints, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Complaints, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 5a-5b)
- Complaints, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  July-Dec. 1943.
- Complaints, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 1a-1b)
  Jan-June, 1943.
- Complaints, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 2a-2e)
- Complaints, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 3a-3b)
  Aug-Dec. 1941.
- Complaints, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 1a-1c)
  Mar.-July 1941.
- Complaints, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 2a-2c)
  Jan.-Feb. 1941.
- Complaints, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 3a-3c)
  June-Dec. 1940.
- Complaints, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 1a-1c)
  Jan-May, 1940.
- Complaints, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 3a-3b)
  April-May 1939.
- Complaints, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  Mar. 1939.
- Complaints, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 1a-1c)
  Jan-Feb. 1939.
- Complaints, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 2a-2b)
  Dec. 1938.
- Complaints, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 3a-3b)
  Oct-Nov. 1938.
- Complaints, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 4a-4b)
  Sept. 1938.
- Complaints, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  Aug. 1938.
- Complaints, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 1a-1b)
  June-July 1938.
- Complaints, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 2a-2b)
  April-May 1938.
- Complaints, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 3a-3c)
  Feb.-Mar. 1938.
- Complaints, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  Jan. 1938.
- Complaints, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Dec. 1937.
- Complaints, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 1a-1b)
  Sept.-Nov. 1937.
- Complaints, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  July-Aug. 1937.
- Complaints, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 3a-3b)
  Apr.-June 1937.
- Complaints, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 4a-4b)
  Jan-Mar. 1937.
- Complaints, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Oct.-Dec. 1936.
- Complaints, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  May-Sept. 1936.
- Complaints, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 2a-2b)
  Jan.-Apr. 1936.
- Complaints, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 3a-3b)
- Complaints. (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Congress of Industrial Organizations (See Committee for Industrial Organizations.) (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Conventions. 27th, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 6a-6f)
- Incl. two Harry S Truman letters. (Box 25, Folder 1a-1d)
- Conventions. 26th, 1947 (Box 25, Folder 2a-2e)
  Incl. Harry S Truman letter
- Conventions. 25th, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 1a-1d)
  Incl. Franklin D. Roosevelt letter.
- Conventions. 24th, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 2a-2d)
- Conventions. 23rd, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 1a-1b)
  22nd, 1934. Incl. Franklin D. Roosevelt letter.
- Cottone, Anthony, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Cotton Garment Conferences, 1937-1944 (Box 27, Folder 3a-3b)
  Incl. minutes of Conference on Dress Situation, 1-26-40; reports; press releases.
- Credentials. (Box 27, Folder 4)
- D, 1947-1951 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- D, 1940-1946 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- D, 1933-1939 (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Destin, Basilio. (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Dewey, Thomas E. (Governor), State of N.Y., 1943-1951 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Donnelly Garment Co. (See Kansas City Jt. Bd.) (Box 27, Folder 10)
- D.D., 1941-1944 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  Incl. affidavits for individuals.
- D.D. V.P., AFL, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 2)
- D.D. V.P., AFL, 1935-1936 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  Jan. 1935-Mar. 1936. Incl. draft of subjects to be considered at Exec. Council meeting of AFL.
- D.D. V.P., AFL, 1934-1936 (Box 28, Folder 4a-4c)
  Oct. 1934-June 1936.
- D.D. V.P., AFL, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  Congratulatory messages to D.D. upon his election to Exec. Council of AFL.
- D.D., 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 6)
- D.D., 1945-1947 (Box 29, Folder 1a-1c)
- D.D., 1942-1944 (Box 29, Folder 2a-2b)
- D.D., 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 3a-3b)
  Incl. messages bet. D.D. & Hannah Haskel (Secy.), when D.D. was away from office, on Union matters.
- D.D. Misc., 1939 (Box 29, Folder 4a-4b)
  Same as ff 3a-3b; also correspondence. w. Frederick F. Umhey.
- D.D. Misc. correspondence., 1937-1938 (Box 29, Folder 5a-5b)
- D.D., 1936 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  Incl. telegrams to D.D. when he was in Europe, from Union officers about CIO controversy and Union's position.
- D.D., 1935 (Box 30, Folder 1a-1b)
- D.D., 1934 (Box 30, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. correspondence. bet. D.D. & Hannah Haskel informing him of Union matters.
- D.D., 1933 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  Same as ff 2a-2b.
- D.D., 1932 (Box 30, Folder 4a-4b)
  Same as ff 2a-2b. Incl. congratulatory messages to D.D. upon being elected President.
- D.D., 1931 (Box 30, Folder 5a-5b)
  General Secretary-Treasurer. Correspondents incl. Abraham Baroff & Benjamin Schlesinger.
- D.D., 1930 (Box 30, Folder 6a-6b)